<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2026 Carl Schwan <carlschwan@kde.org>
SPDX-License-Identifier: CC0-1.0
-->
<component type="icon-theme">
  <id>org.kde.oxygentheme</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>LGPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <url type="homepage">https://develop.kde.org/frameworks/oxygen-icons/</url>
  <url type="translate">https://community.kde.org/Get_Involved/translation</url>
  <url type="contribute">https://community.kde.org/Get_Involved</url>
  <url type="donation">https://kde.org/donate/?app=oxygen</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?product=Oxygen</url>
  <name>Oxygen Icons</name>
  <name xml:lang="ar">أيقونات أكسجين</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Icones Oxygen</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">Icones Oxygen</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Iconos Oxígeno</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Icônes du thème « Oxygen »</name>
  <name xml:lang="he">סמלי חמצן</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Icone di Oxygen</name>
  <name xml:lang="ka">Oxygen Icons</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">Oxygen 아이콘</name>
  <name xml:lang="lt">Oxygen piktogramos</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Oxygen-pictogrammen</name>
  <name xml:lang="nn">Oxygen-ikon</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">Ícones Oxygen</name>
  <name xml:lang="ro">Pictograme Oxygen</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Ikony Oxygen</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">Ikone Oxygen</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">Oksijen Simgeleri</name>
  <name xml:lang="ug">ئوكسىگېن سىنبەلگە</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Піктограми Oxygen</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-CN">Oxygen 轻氧图标</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">Oxygen 圖示</name>
  <summary>A free and open source icon theme to use with the Oxygen Plasma style</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ar">سمة أيقونات حرة ومفتوحة المصدر للاستخدام مع نمط بلازما الأكسجين.</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Un tema d'icones de codi lliure i obert que es fa servir amb l'estil Oxygen del Plasma</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Un tema d'icones de codi lliure i obert que s'utilitza amb l'estil Oxygen de Plasma</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Tema de iconos libre y de código abierto para usar con el estilo Oxígeno de Plasma</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Un thème d'icônes libre et « Open source » à utiliser avec le style « Oxygen » de Plasma</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="he">ערכת סמלים חופשית בקוד פתוח לשימוש עם סגנון חמצן פלזמה</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Un tema di icone gratuito e open source da utilizzare con lo stile Oxygen di Plasma</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ka">თავისუფალი და ღია წყაროს მქონე ხატულების თემა, რომელიც Plasma-ის სტილში Oxygen გამოიყენება</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="lt">Nemokamas, atvirojo kodo piktogramų apipavidalinimas, skirtas naudoti kartu su Oxygen Plasma stiliumi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Een gratis en open-source pictogramthema voor gebruik met de Oxygen Plasma-stijl.</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nn">Eit fritt ikontema for bruk saman med Oxygen Plasma-stilen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Um tema de ícones gratuito e de código aberto para usar com o estilo Oxygen Plasma.</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ro">Tematică de pictograme liberă și cu sursă deschisă de folosit cu stilul Plasma Oxygen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Voľná a otvorená téma ikon na použitie so štýlom Oxygen pre Plasmu</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Prosta in odprtokodna tema ikon za uporabo s slogom Plasma Oxygen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Oksijen Plasma biçemi ile kullanılmak üzere ücretsiz ve açık kaynaklı bir simge teması</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Вільна тема з відкритим початковим кодом для використання зі стилем Плазми Oxygen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-CN">适合与 Oxygen 轻氧 Plasma 主题搭配使用的自由开源图标主题</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-TW">搭配 Plasma 風格 Oxygen 的自由開源圖示主題</summary>
  <description>
    <p>Oxygen Icons is a freedesktop.org compatible icon theme originally developed for the KDE Plasma desktop environment in combination with the Oxygen Style. It features smooth gradients, soft shadows, and a slightly glossy look.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">أيقونات أكسجين هي سمة أيقونات متوافقة مع freedesktop.org تم تطويرها أصلاً لبيئة سطح المكتب كيدي بلازما بالاقتران مع نمط أكسجين. يتميز بتدرجات سلسة، وظلال ناعمة، ومظهر لامع قليلاً.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Les icones Oxygen és un tema d'icones compatible amb freedesktop.org desenvolupat originalment per a l'entorn d'escriptori Plasma de KDE en combinació amb l'estil Oxygen. Presenta degradats suaus, ombres suaus i un aspecte lleugerament brillant.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Les icones Oxygen és un tema d'icones compatible amb freedesktop.org desenvolupat originalment per a l'entorn d'escriptori Plasma de KDE en combinació amb l'estil Oxygen. Presenta degradats suaus, ombres suaus i un aspecte lleugerament brillant.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Iconos Oxígeno es un tema de iconos compatibles con freedesktop.org desarrollado originalmente para el entorno de escritorio Plasma de KDE en combinación con el estilo Oxígeno. Presenta degradados suaves, sombras delicadas y un aspecto ligeramente brillante.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Le thème d'icônes « Oxygen » est compatible avec le thème « freedesktop.org » initialement développé pour l'environnement de bureau KDE Plasma en combinaison avec le style « Oxygen ». Il présente des dégradés doux, des ombres légères et un aspect légèrement brillant.</p>
    <p xml:lang="he">סמלי חמצן היא סדרת סמלים תואמת freedesktop.org שפותחה במקור עבור סביבת שולחן העבודה פלזמה מבית KDE בשילוב סגנון חמצן. היא מציעה מדרגים חלקים, הצללות רכות ומראה מעט מזוגג.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Icone di Oxygen è un tema di icone compatibile con freedesktop.org originariamente sviluppato per l'ambiente desktop KDE Plasma in combinazione con lo stile Oxygen. Presenta sfumature uniformi, ombre morbide e un aspetto leggermente lucido.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">Oxygen Icons არის freedesktop.org-თან თავსებადი ხატულების თემა, რომელიც თავიდან KDE Plasma სამუშაო გარემოსთვის შემუშავდა სტილთან Oxygen ერთად. მას გააჩნია გლუვი გრადიენტები, რბილი ჩრდილები და ოდნავ პრიალა იერი.</p>
    <p xml:lang="lt">Oxygen piktogramos yra su freedesktop.org suderinamas piktogramų apipavidalinimas, kuris nuo pat pradžių kartu su Oxygen stiliumi buvo sukurtas KDE Plasma darbalaukio aplinkai. Oxygen piktogramos pateikia glotnius gradientus, švelnius šešėlius bei šiek tiek žvilgančią išvaizdą.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Oxygen-pictogrammen is een pictogramthema dat compatibel is met freedesktop.org en oorspronkelijk is ontwikkeld voor de KDE Plasma-bureaubladomgeving in combinatie met de Oxygen-stijl. Het kenmerkt zich door vloeiende kleurovergangen, zachte schaduwen en een licht glanzende uitstraling.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nn">Oxygen-ikon er eit freedesktop.org-kompatibelt ikontema opphavleg utvikla for KDE Plasma og Oxygen-stilen. Det har jamne fargeovergangar, mjuke skuggar og lett glans.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Ícones Oxygen é um tema de ícones compatível com freedesktop.org, originalmente desenvolvido para o ambiente de desktop KDE Plasma em combinação com o Estilo Oxygen. Apresenta gradientes suaves, sombras delicadas e um aspecto levemente brilhante.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ro">Pictogramele Oxygen sunt o tematică de pictograme compatibilă cu freedesktop.org, dezvoltată inițial pentru mediul de birou KDE Plasma în combinație cu stilul Oxygen. Aceasta are gradienți lini, umbre moi și un aspect puțin lucios.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Oxygen Icons je téma ikon kompatibilná s freedesktop.org, ktorá bola pôvodne vyvinutá pre desktopové prostredie KDE Plasma v kombinácii so štýlom Oxygen. Vyznačuje sa plynulými prechodmi, jemnými tieňmi a mierne lesklým vzhľadom.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Oxygen Icons je tema ikon, združljiva s freedesktop.org, prvotno razvita za namizno okolje KDE Plasma v kombinaciji s slogom Oxygen. Ima gladke prelive, mehke sence in rahlo sijoč videz.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Oksijen Simgeleri, özgün olarak KDE Plasma masaüstü ortamı için Oksijen biçemi ile birlikte geliştirilmiş, freedesktop.org ile uyumlu bir simge temasıdır. Pürüzsüz geçişler, yumuşak gölgeler ve hafif parlak bir görünüme sahiptir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Піктограми Oxygen — це тема піктограм, сумісна з freedesktop.org, спочатку розроблена для стільничного середовища Плазма KDE у поєднанні зі стилем Oxygen. Вона містить плавні градієнти, м'які тіні та злегка глянцевий вигляд.</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">Oxygen 图标主题是一款兼容 freedesktop.org 规范的图标主题，专为在 KDE Plasma 桌面环境下与 Oxygen 轻氧样式主题搭配使用。它的图标具有平滑的渐变、柔和的阴影以及略带光泽的外观。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">Oxygen 圖示是一套與 freedesktop.org 標準相容的圖示主題，原先為使用 Oxygen 風格的 KDE Plasma 桌面環境開發。它提供較柔和的漸層、柔和陰影與類似玻璃的外觀。</p>
  </description>
  <developer id="kde.org">
    <name translate="no">KDE</name>
  </developer>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image type="source">https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/oxygen/kmail-oxygen.png</image>
      <caption>Screenshot of KMail with the Oxygen style and icon theme.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ar">لقطة شاشة تطبيق بريدك بنمط وأيقونات أكسجين.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Captura de pantalla del KMail amb el tema d'estil i icones Oxygen.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Captura de pantalla de KMail amb el tema d'estil i icones Oxygen.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Captura de pantalla de KMail con el estilo y tema de iconos Oxígeno.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Capture d'écran de KMail avec le style et le thème d'icônes « Oxygen ».</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="he">צילום מסך של KMail עם סגנון וערכת סמלים מסוג חמצן.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Schermata di KMail con lo stile Oxygen e il tema delle icone.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">KMail-ის ეკრანის ანაბეჭდი Oxygen სტილითა და ხატულას თემით.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="lt">Ekrano kopija, kurioje programa KMail naudoja Oxygen stilių ir piktogramų apipavidalinimą.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Schermafdruk van KMail met de Oxygen-stijl en het -pictogramthema.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Skjermbilete av KMail med Oxygen-stil og ikontemaet.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Captura de tela do KMail com o estilo Oxygen e o tema de ícones.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Captură de ecran cu KMail având Stilul și tematica de pictograme Oxygen.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">Snímka obrazovky aplikácie KMail so štýlom a témou ikon Oxygen.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Posnetek zaslona KMaila s slogom in temo ikon Oxygen.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">K Posta’nın Oksijen biçemi ve simgeleri ile ekran görüntüsü</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Знімок вікна KMail зі стилем і темою піктограм Oxygen.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">使用 Oxygen 样式与图标主题的 KMail 屏幕截图。</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-TW">KMail 使用 Oxygen 風格與圖示主題的螢幕截圖。</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="6.2.0" date="2026-05-19">
      <description>
        <p>This new release adds many new symbolic icons for the system tray.</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">تضيف هذه الإصدارة الجديدة أيقونات رمزية لصينية النظام.</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquest llançament nou afegeix moltes icones simbòliques noves per a la safata del sistema.</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Este llançament nou afig moltes icones simbòliques noves per a la safata del sistema.</p>
        <p xml:lang="es">Esta nueva versión añade muchos iconos simbólicos nuevos para la bandeja del sistema.</p>
        <p xml:lang="fr">Cette nouvelle version ajoute de nombreuses nouvelles icônes symboliques pour la boite à miniature.</p>
        <p xml:lang="he">המהדורה החדשה הזאת מוסיפה מגוון סמלים סמליים לשורת המערכת.</p>
        <p xml:lang="it">Questa nuova versione aggiunge molte nuove icone simboliche per il vassoio di sistema.</p>
        <p xml:lang="ka">ეს ახალი ვერსია ამატებს ბევრ ახალ სიმბოლური ხატულას სისტემური კუთხისთვის.</p>
        <p xml:lang="lt">Ši nauja laida prideda daugybę naujų simbolinių piktogramų, skirtų sistemos dėklui.</p>
        <p xml:lang="nl">Deze nieuwe uitgave voegt veel nieuwe symbolische pictogrammen toe aan het systeemvak.</p>
        <p xml:lang="nn">I denne utgåva er det komme mange nye symbolikon for systemtrauet.</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta nova versão adiciona muitos novos ícones simbólicos para a bandeja do sistema.</p>
        <p xml:lang="ro">Această ediție nouă adaugă multe pictograme simbolice noi pentru tava de sistem.</p>
        <p xml:lang="sk">Toto nové vydanie pridáva mnoho nových symbolických ikon pre systémovú lištu.</p>
        <p xml:lang="sl">Ta nova izdaja dodaja veliko novih simboličnih ikon za sistemski pladenj.</p>
        <p xml:lang="tr">Bu yeni yayım, sistem tepsisi için birçok yeni sembolik simgeler ekler.</p>
        <p xml:lang="uk">У цьому випуску додано багато нових символічних піктограм для системного лотка.</p>
        <p xml:lang="zh-CN">这一新版本为系统托盘追加了大量符号化图标。</p>
        <p xml:lang="zh-TW">這個新版本為許多系統匣新增許多符號圖示。</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
